我們繼續第一次聖誕節
第一半的第一次聖誕節是講什麼呢
第一半是講很多不同的教會裏面的問題
是什麼問題
這個教會有什麼問題 記不記得
Shout it out 有什麼問題
有什麼問題
完美的 是不是
Kaleb 有什麼問題
CY 有什麼問題
說吧 每個人都說一個 如果不是的話
Incest 男女關係是有些問題的
還有呢
Let's go to the next slide
他們又覺得自己很驕傲
I'm better than everybody else
有不同的dispute
你搶了我的豬扒包 記不記得
還有呢 他們不保持自己的身體聖誕
他們又告你你告我
然後他們又說我們犧牲了這些食物
他們的偶像 我吃還是不吃好呢
吃還是不吃好呢
所以第一半的第一次聖誕節
是保羅直接提出那些不同的教會的不同的問題
第二是指示教會的指導
第二半是指示教會的指導
So we're gonna read together
the next part
let's read the next slide together
about spiritual gifts
brothers and sisters
I do not want you to be uninformed
you know that when you were pagans
somehow or other
you were influenced and led astray
to mute idols
therefore I want you to know
that no one
who is speaking by the spirit of God
says Jesus speaks first
Jesus is the Lord
except by the Holy Spirit
there are different kinds of gifts
but the same spirit distributes them
there are different kinds of service
but the same Lord
there are different kinds of working
but all in them and in every form
it is the same God at work
Ok 好 首先呢
這裏呢 保羅就說
the gifts of the spirit
gifts of the spirit
這個spirit
這個spirit 是誰的spirit
Holy Spirit
和你旁邊那個
分享一下
Who is the Holy Spirit
你旁邊那個
很快 30 seconds
Who is the Holy Spirit
Ok 好
誰覺得
他的朋友
認識聖靈是誰
Raise your hand
你覺得
Kid 知嗎
Kid 好 上來
I am joking
嚇死他
Ok 誰覺得他的朋友
很認識聖靈是誰
CY Caleb
Ok 還有呢
沒什麼
Gabriel is understanding
Let's go to the next slide
on who is the Holy Spirit
考考你們
So there is three options
第一呢 Who is the Holy Spirit
A mysterious energy field
created by life that binds the galaxy together
Ok
這個是第一個option
Mysterious energy field
第二呢 是a force that is unpredictable
Ok 第二個option
第三個option呢
The Holy Spirit is a divine person
A person that is divine
Ok 好
我給你們十秒
你選一二還是三
我們會
一二三就舉起
你覺得一二還是三
不緊要
你wrong都ok
Let's go ready
一二三 舉
Higher higher
Ok
Ok two
Ok I see some two
Uncle Stanley 是one
Ok 好
Ok
誰選了A
A是什麼
What is the definition of A
知道嗎
A是什麼
這個是Star Wars
A mysterious energy field
that is created by life
that binds the galaxy together
這個是Yoda
I can control the force move objects
這個是definition of
the force of the
Star Wars
這個不是Holy Spirit
不要搞錯
Holy Spirit不是
created by life
that binds the galaxy together
Ok
第二 誰選了第二呢
第二是什麼
A force that is unpredictable
在describe什麼
What is it describing
Describe什麼
A force that is unpredictable
The weather
What is heading towards China
什麼 叫什麼
巴
叫什麼
Big Typhoon
Super El Nino
A force that is unpredictable
That is unpredictable
所以呢
如果你選了The first two options
不是聖靈
Ok
聖靈是誰
聖靈是
The third person of the Trinity
有聖父 聖子
和聖靈
God the Father, the Son
and the Holy Spirit
The Father is not the Son
The Son is not the Holy Spirit
The Holy Spirit is not the Father
Ok
三為一體
Three are God
明白嗎
所以呢 聖靈是很重要的
聖靈是很重要的
它是幫手
In creation 是什麼
He is hovering over the waters
In creation
Let's read it together
我們讀中文
Ok
首先呢 耶穌說什麼
祂走的時候
祂會差遣誰
祂會差遣The Holy Spirit
聖靈 是不是
這個聖靈是怎樣的
Describe 聖靈
The Spirit of Truth
所以呢 聖靈
是幫我們認識
真理
所以之前 保羅就說
Before you believed
in idols that were
mute
之前
Where are they
Greece 那些人
Worship 誰
What did they worship back then
The Greek Gods
Zeus 還有什麼
Venus
Athena
All these different gods
保羅就說 這些Gods
是不說話的
They are mute, they cannot speak
其實 這些idols
是誰創造的
是人創造的
They carve them out of stone
但是你信的神
是聖靈
聖靈
是說真理
God is the God of Truth
The Holy Spirit is the one who helps us
understand the truth
這些不同的Temple
在Greek那裡
In Corinth
They worshiped Zeus, Athena
不同的Gods
Paul is saying
The Holy Spirit
Helps you understand who the true God is
Who the true God is
我們繼續
Next slide
It says
There are different kinds of service
But the same Lord
Different kinds of gifts
But the same Spirit distributes them
There are different kinds of working
But all in them
And everyone
It is the same God that is at work
保羅在說什麼
這個聖靈
It is working in unity
It is working in unity with who?
聖靈和誰合作?
和聖父
和聖子
一起合作
They work together in unity
他們一起
The Spirit's job is to distribute gifts
The Spirit's job is to
help people to serve
The Spirit's job is to help
in the different workings
But it is all through the Holy Spirit
聖靈是給不同的gifts
But it is through the Holy Spirit
All through the Holy Spirit
有不同的恩賜
But it is through one Spirit
有不同的侍奉
But it is through the Holy Spirit
In terms of working
The God is working in different ways
But it is through the Holy Spirit
所以保羅現在是emphasize
So Paul is emphasizing
The Holy Spirit is working
In many ways
聖靈不只是
和中國人傳福音
他不只是和猶太人傳福音
He is sharing the gospel to
all people, to the ends of the earth
明白嗎?
So, many gifts
to share the gospel to many people
But it is the same
Spirit, same Holy Spirit
that is working
好,第二個question
Who receives spiritual gifts?
我們第一個
第一節我們說
Now the gifts of the Spirit
I do not want you to be uninformed
保羅是說
The gifts of the Holy Spirit
你覺得誰是
Receive the gifts of the Holy Spirit
你和你旁邊那個又分享
Who receives the gifts of the Holy Spirit?
Ok, 誰覺得
他的朋友是很
Understand who
Receives spiritual gifts
Ok, I will ask another question
誰覺得他
Received the spiritual gifts?
Raise your hand
誰覺得他有Receive the spiritual gifts?
Ok, ok
沒有舉手的覺得
不清楚什麼是
Spiritual gift, 還是不清楚
他Received, ok, it's ok
It's ok, 我們讀
Verse 7, let's read verse 7 together
1, 2, 3
Now to each one, the
manifestation of the Spirit is given
for the common good
Ok, 喏
保羅呢,這裡就說
To each one, that is
to each believer
The Spirit
will give a spiritual gift
In Ephesians
Chapter 2, it also says
Right, that the Holy Spirit
Is a guarantee
for those
who are in Christ Jesus
Ok, 所以你認識了
日神呢,你
If you have confessed Jesus
to be your Lord and Saviour
Right, 你個人
救主呢,你是有
Receive the Holy Spirit
And if you receive the Holy Spirit
You receive also
the gifts of
the Holy Spirit
So, the next slide, the Holy Spirit
gives spiritual gifts to each believer
for building up
the body of Christ
Ok, and then we also see
later in the verses
that the Holy Spirit gives gifts to each believer
as he discerns
and for
the common good
For the common good
Ok, 現在是discussion time
我們有兩個問題
第一個問題是
What is your experience of the Holy Spirit been like?
你有沒有經歷過聖靈
在你的生命?
你有沒有經歷過聖靈在你的生命?
第二呢,是你覺得
What is the difference
between natural talent
and spiritual gift?
Natural talent and spiritual gift
Ok,我們有四分鐘
五分鐘分享
有些組可以分享一下
有沒有經歷過聖靈?
我好難講,我只記得
Natural talent 就應該本身是natural
但屬靈的因次
Spiritual gift 就令到你自己
更加似耶穌
Ok, spiritual gift make you more like Jesus
Ok, that's interesting
Ok,首先我們answer
第一個question,有沒有經歷過聖靈?
有沒有經歷過聖靈
有時候聖靈會給你一種想法
想法是甚麼?
想法是
你自己的心態
MING PAO CANADA | MING PAO TORONTO